[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 30]
These are your mother's clothes.
Yes.
When your mother sang "Tale of the Pipa,"
she wore these.
And only you
are worthy of them.
When I
married her back then,
I was obsessed with her performance.
But
after I married her,
I never saw her wear them again.
And she never came back.
My mother
can never come back.
Yes, yes.
The dead can't come back to life.
She can never come back.
Yes.
But it's good that you're back, Qingyuan.
My biggest regret is that
I never held you when you were a baby.
I never heard you call me father.
I owe you so much.
But I remember one thing.
-One time, a kid -Wait for me!
ran into me
with open arms.
"Uncle!"
But I could tell at a glance
that it was you.
You're the child of Chunqing and me.
You looked just like her.
Those eyes
and that little nose.
You called me uncle...
Qingyuan,
let me tell you some great news.
Xie Qingyuan,
receive the imperial edict!
The Emperor has pardoned
the Xie family's crimes.
He pardoned us!
Qingyuan,
do you know
this means that from now on,
in all of Hengtang,
I, Xie Shu, am the only powerful one left?
It's ours now.
I assure you,
this is more glorious than all
the Xie family's ancestors combined.
More than a hundred, even a thousand times.
Congratulations, Father,
on protecting the dignity
of the Xie family.
Father, do you feel joy
in your heart?
Of course I do.
You're just a child.
You don't understand at all.
Do you know how powerful
Shen Zhibai used to be?
Do you know what kind of person
Eunuch Xia was?
He wielded great power in the court!
Do you know
how arrogant
Hu Xing was?
Those three families
weren't the only ones riding roughshod over me.
There were also Lord Zhang,
Lord Li, Lord Wang,
thousands of them!
Do you know that
they all fell?
And the only one left
is me, the weakest of them all!
Xie Shu!
Can you believe it?
Your father is
so powerful!
Below one person and above everyone else!
From now on,
Hengtang
can be completely called Xietang.
This court belongs to me.
Oh wait, I forgot.
You've already married that boy, Shen Run.
But it doesn't matter.
I'll always be your father.
It's all yours.
Give Shen Run half of it.
Yes.
You are my father.
When I was young, I longed for
a father's love.
It was so easily obtained by others,
but I didn't have it.
I fear that, in this lifetime,
I'm no longer worthy of possessing this love.
No, my good daughter.
Because my father
killed my mother!
What are you talking about?
The moment you killed my mother
that night, 9 years ago.
It reminds me
in my dreams every night that
you're not my father,
but my enemy!
Every time you tell me
how much you loved my mother,
I feel disgusted.
I'm waiting,
waiting for the day
I take everything from you
and destroy you.
You've killed too many people.
Your hands are covered in blood.
Do you still remember
who the first person you killed was?
Uncle.
Money.
I can give you the money.
But
can you
stop bullying Chunqing?
She is your daughter after all.
Cut the crap. Cough out the money.
Are you even human?
Please,
stop harassing Chunqing.
Stop harassing Chunqing.
What did you say?
I harass her?
I can even marry her!
What?
Let me tell you,
she's not my biological daughter.
You...
You're worse than a beast!
I can tell you a little secret too.
You
are my biological son.
Don't believe me?
Go back and ask Old Madam yourself.
My good son.
I will come look for you again.
If you don't want Chunqing to know,
get me more money!
Remember,
in this life,
you can never get rid of me!
I have money!
Son!
Did you get the money?
Money.
That's right.
That's my
good son.
Tell me,
what was I doing before?
I
should have told you long ago.
I want to trade it for Chunqing.
Can I?
No way.
I'd be taking a huge loss!
Such a huge loss!
Impossible! Don't even think about it!
You...
Unfilial son!
How dare you kill your own father...
Chunqing was burdened by him
and never had a single good day.
I did it to save Chunqing.
You must never tell anyone.
Never tell anyone.
I beg you.
Shen.
Jingzhi?
What's going on?
Chunqing.
There are many things
I’ll fill you in on at a later time.
Now I only want to ask you one thing.
If I ask for my mother's permission,
will you marry me?
I...
Will you?
Of course I will.
I don't care about
Jin Chunqing.
I also don't care if you're the biological son
of the Xie family
or not.
But,
this Shen Zhibai
holds the key to Hengtang’s future and the imperial court’s politics.
[Respectfully submitted in grief by Jin Chunqing]
She has dug her own grave with this letter.
My dear brother-in-law.
Will you
kill her
and continue to enjoy your wealth and glory,
or will you give up everything you have now
and go back to your birth parents to sell charcoal and forge iron?
The choice is yours.
[Respectfully submitted in grief by Jin Chunqing]
But
once you choose a path,
you must walk it to the end.
Mother is sick.
She asked me to visit you.
It's been 9 years.
You should hate me.
How could I hate you?
I was all alone since childhood.
My father
was that kind of person.
I thought I could never escape that fate.
But you barged into my life.
You ended my suffering.
No matter your reason,
you saved me after all.
Against all pressure,
you married me into the Xie Residence.
Even though they eventually forced me
to leave the Xie Residence,
I know
you did it to protect me.
They hurt you.
They all deserve to die!
I don't blame anyone.
You shouldn't blame them either.
They beat me so hard.
But surprisingly,
they didn't kill the little girl in my belly.
It's God's will.
Jingzhi.
We have a child.
I saw her.
She's lovely.
She looks just like you.
Chunqing.
It's fine.
I'll do it.
You go back and rest first.
Jingzhi.
Actually, for the past 9 years,
I've been very content.
I lived very happily.
Whenever I look into our child's eyes,
I feel like I can see your reflection.
Whenever I look at her,
it feels as though
we’re still happily together, as if we had
never been separated.
It's too hot.
Wait a bit before drinking.
Wait a little.
Actually,
after I finished writing that letter,
I figured it out.
Between us,
it seems like you are living a better life.
But in reality,
you are the pitiful one.
When I found out
I was a daughter of the Xie family,
for a moment,
I also saw that cage.
But when I walked out
and looked back,
I realized it was
completely empty.
There was nothing there.
Jingzhi.
I'm leaving.
I plan to take Yunya
and leave Hengtang.
We'll settle down in a place
with warm springs and blooming flowers.
I will often miss
how you looked when we first met.
Back then,
you were still with Shen Zhibai.
You had endless things to talk about
and do every day.
I didn't understand any of it,
but I loved listening to them.
The Hengtang you described
was truly wonderful.
I wish I could live there
for just one day.
♪ In a rush to seek me, she neglects her grooming ♪
Chunqing...
There's no turning back for me.
In the next life,
let's be husband and wife again.
What's going on?
Hurry, run!
What was that sound?
After them!
Up there!
Move!
Let's go.
Who told you these?
Who is spreading these rumors?
You've got it wrong!
You actually believe them?
You killed my mother.
You killed your biological father
and adoptive mother.
Your close friend Shen Zhibai
kept your secret for a lifetime,
but you had his entire family executed.
You used their blood
to pave the way for your career.
Well?
Are you
happy now?
Get out!
Who told you this?
Who told you?
Bastard. I'll kill him!
Qingyuan, no.
Bastard!
Give it to me!
You want it?
Here.
This kind of trash,
I can easily forge a thousand copies,
even ten thousand copies.
Are you scared?
Get out!
You are scared.
This letter was kept by Hu Wenzhuo for 9 years,
but you never dared to look back at it once.
Because you wanted to forget
why you wanted to kill my mother.
You wanted to forget those filthy thoughts.
But today,
I will make you remember.
I want you to remember
everything my mother said forever.
When I first met Xie Shu,
he still had light in his eyes.
That light
once gave me hope in the abyss.
Come on, Shen, Jingzhi.
Let's go
and see
what's for dinner.
We'll listen to you.
Okay.
The new Hengtang he painted together with Shen Zhibai
was something I yearned for.
Those days were the happiest time of my life.
But the Xie family's secret
will eventually swallow that light inch by inch
and turn him into another person.
Rather than saying
[Mr. Xie Jingzhi]
I want to save Shen Zhibai,
it's more accurate to say that the person I want to rescue
is that pitiful person pushed into the abyss by fate,
my once deeply loved husband,
Xie Shu.
Jingzhi.
There is still time.
Save Shen Zhibai,
and help me
save yourself.
Good.
Very good.
Qingyuan,
I swear that every word I've said
to you today is the truth.
No matter what,
I am,
you could say,
the one who killed your mother,
the woman I loved the most.
Your father, in this life,
has seen countless women.
But I
have only ever loved this one woman,
your mother,
Chunqing.
But I actually killed her.
Isn't it absurd?
Who else?
Shen Zhibai,
my family, my friends...
Everyone around me.
I've killed too many.
Too many of them.
I tried to pen it all down.
I wrote them down and recalled them,
but I simply couldn't keep up.
After some time,
I plan to revise the Xie family genealogy.
Didn't the Xie family say
that Jin Chunqing couldn't enter the genealogy?
Too bad! I'm including her.
Let me tell you,
I'm going to include her right now,
and I'll write it myself.
Child, do you know how I'll write it?
Hasn't their Xie clan been around for a century?
Starting from their very first ancestor...
His ancestor's mother,
foster mother, and biological mother
will all be called Jin Chunqing.
After that, every generation of
their head madam will all be called Jin Chunqing!
I want everyone in the world to know
that your mother's name
is Jin Chunqing!
To avenge your mother,
I'll make sure every generation
of the Xie family was raised
by Jin Chunqing!
Those bastards of the Xie family!
They took my Chunqing away...
Those bastards!
I'll make sure they were all raised by your mother...
Isn't it satisfying?
I'll avenge your mother...
Chunqing...
There is no chance anymore.
I don't need anyone to give me a chance.
Look at this.
The imperial edict.
His Majesty has pardoned all my crimes.
Is that so?
His Majesty pardoned you
because of the Xie family's achievements,
and the Xie family's prestige in the Northern Frontier.
Xie Shu.
But this doesn't mean
you are still a member of the Xie family in the future.
Xie Qingyuan is not only your daughter,
but now also His Majesty's designated
new matriarch of the Xie family.
Are you forcing me to make a decision?
I wouldn't dare.
But Xie Shu
poisoned his beloved,
killed his own father,
drove his adoptive mother to her death,
harmed the loyal and good,
and preyed on the people.
With such evil deeds to his name,
if he still receives your grace,
I fear the world
will doubt Your Majesty's sense of justice.
If Xie Shu is removed, Hengtang will fall into chaos.
You are a man who has already died once.
How many lives do you have left to clean up this mess for me?
It's true that I only have one life,
but Shen Zhibai
and Zhou Pei'an were the same.
But if I dare not
break the deadlock and implement the new policies today,
in the future,
how many more loyal subjects must die,
and how many more 9 years must we wait
before Your Majesty
makes a decision?
If Your Majesty is worried that no one will take over Hengtang,
I would like to recommend someone.
Chen Qingyuan
is the only bloodline of the Xie family.
And the Xie family under Qingyuan's reign
will surely innovate and change.
Please make a wise decision, Your Majesty.
Good.
What an innovation and change.
Pass on my decree.
Commander of the Palace Guard,
Shen Run,
shall lead and investigate Xie Shu's case.
I also appoint Chen Qingyuan
as the matriarch of the Xie family.
Her?
A mere girl,
as the matriarch of the Xie family?
Is that possible?
If a woman could be the head of the family,
would Lu Lingshu have had
the heart to exchange his own daughter, Chunqing,
for a poor boy like me back then?
Brat.
Ask Qingyuan
what I just said.
No matter how much she annoys me,
I will always
and forever be her father.
Everything I have
also belongs to her.
And what she owns
is also yours in the future.
What did you come to this world for,
brat?
Fame and wealth!
I can make them yours in an instant!
We are a family,
what are we fighting for?
I don't care about the things
the Xie family has.
I have already distributed them to those who need them more.
Qingyuan has already given everything the Xie family owns
to the refugees and the people
to promote the new policies in Hengtang.
You're lying to me.
What new policies?
Distributing my property?
Impossible.
Who would give away their own mountains of gold and silver
to others?
How absurd.
Xie Shu.
Do you still remember
this silver coin?
Shen,
the corrupt official we impeached together
has finally been eradicated.
I specially minted this silver coin.
This is the beginning of our efforts
to build a better life for the people.
Brother,
as long as the two of us
stand united and work wholeheartedly
for the court and for the people,
we'll surely make those corrupt officials in Hengtang
spit out every tale of silver they took!
Yes, also.
Brother,
as for the policies you wrote about in your articles:
measuring the land,
equalizing taxes,
and collecting based on acreage.
These are great policies.
No matter how difficult,
we must implement them.
Brother,
as long as we are united,
these wishes
can all be realized!
Definitely!
The new equalization policy...
We were young and ignorant.
Laughable.
How laughable...
Is it laughable?
What you call laughable
is now on the verge of becoming reality.
The new equalization policy
will be piloted in Hengtang
starting today.
If successful,
it will be implemented nationwide.
Xie Shu.
We are going to burn down your Xie family.
What do you want?
I endured humiliation all my life
and just acquired the family estate.
I haven't even enjoyed it for a day,
and you are going to burn it down?
Are you that greedy?
Wait- wait!
It was all yours to begin with.
My daughter,
can't you even leave me
a bite to eat?
Before you killed those innocent people,
did you ever think of leaving them a bite to eat?
Have you quelled the flames
of those vengeful spirits?
For my mother,
Jin Chunqing.
For my father,
Shen Zhibai.
And for those countless
wronged souls you killed,
We will return it all to you.
I originally planned
to teach you
one last lesson before I die.
I wanted to teach you
to pay the price
for your sins.
But now...
I can't save you anymore.
Back then, I had a dream during the Lantern Festival.
All flowers faded during the full moon.
The full moon refers to Qingyuan.
I should have known.
The century-old Xie family
was destined to be destroyed
as soon as Qingyuan appeared.
So, there really is such a thing
as divine will in this world!
My lifelong obsession
amounts to nothing
in the end...
Nothing.
Yet it cost so many lives.
The blood on my hands can never be washed clean.
So be it.
[Fuyu Pavilion]
Let the fire destroy it.
Let it destroy everything!
Chunqing!
Mother!
I am here to atone!
I didn't expect
that he would choose to die here.
Perhaps it’s only when a person is dying
that they truly come to understand certain things.
He probably wanted to atone.
[Spring comes to Changmen]
♪ Spring comes to the long gate, green grass sprouts ♪
♪ Red plums bear dewdrops, bright and serene ♪
[Zhongwu Hall]
♪ Year by year, time drifts along ♪
♪ Warmth and chill of mortal meet and part ♪
♪ No need to heed the wind's soft whisper and ask about your return ♪
♪ Wild geese soar through deep clouds, waiting for the moon to rest ♪
When I left Hengtang,
I made a promise to Fourth Sister
that I would open Yunji Snacks branches
all over the world.
♪ Old memories lie heavy, haunting every dream ♪
And now,
there is even a branch in the capital.
I consider that I have kept my promise.
♪ Rises and falls take turns ♪
[Zhongwu Hall]
The old Marquis passed away,
♪ Phases of the moon, unplanned to wax and wane ♪
and Old Madam went to a manor to recuperate.
The Marquis is busy in the army,
♪ Count fallen blooms, yet never count all pains of parting ♪
leaving early and returning late every day.
Madam, you're left alone
in the residence.
♪ You, tender yet sharp, with thorns by your side ♪
♪ Like a dim yet blazing candle ♪
Teacher, this hairpin of yours
is elegant and unique.
♪ The wind and rain sigh, the road stretches far ♪
It complements the flower shadows in the poem
and adds a touch of tranquility.
♪ Blossoms drift with streams, affections softly stir ♪
Even if you praise me more,
♪ Half real, half illusion; one cup of spring awakes me ♪
you still have to pay for the book.
It's strange.
Every shop
looks almost the same.
But once you enter,
they are all different inside.
The climate and geography are different,
dietary habits are different,
and individual constitutions differ even more.
Naturally, every shop
has to adjust its prescriptions according to the location.
Only then
can it be considered prescribing the right medicine.
Adjusting prescriptions according to the location?
Go put out the light.
Madam.
Why are you resting so early?
In the past,
didn't you always leave a light on for the Marquis
until the third watch?
What if
he comes back early tonight?
What if...
There is no need.
[Zhongwu Hall]
Even if the light is on,
it only illuminates
an empty room.
The money for the book is a small matter.
I passed by your place and saw the door ajar.
May I sit with you for a while?
In your life,
you won't just meet Mr. Zhou.
♪ If the wind softly whispers your name ♪
You will meet so many people.
You will live a good life.
♪ If my heart softly hears your voice ♪
[Zhongwu Hall]
♪ I'm still here, holding on to our memories ♪
♪ Quietly waiting in the passage of time for a reply ♪
Darling.
♪ Listening to every word, every line, everything about you ♪
Darling!
♪ Your gentle breath, the traces left by longing ♪
The arrow's fletching
tore through the cloth you wrapped for me.
Please, darling,
repair it for me one more time.
♪ No sight could ever compare to you, forever in my heart ♪
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become part of your journey ♪
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
My wife
is so impressive.
It seems your medical skills
are catching up with your mother's.
♪ If the wind softly whispers your name ♪
♪ If my heart softly hears your voice ♪
♪ I'm still here, holding on to our memories ♪
[Where grass turns green, red plum buds]
♪ Quietly waiting in the passage of time for a reply ♪
♪ Listening to every word, every line, everything about you ♪
♪ Your gentle breath, the traces left by longing ♪
♪ No sight could ever compare to you, forever in my heart ♪
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become part of your journey ♪
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
[Spring comes to Changmen, where grass turns green Red plum buds just starting to bloom.]
[Jade-green tea, ground fine as dust. A sip at dawn breaks a dream and stirs a cup of spring.]
♪ No sight could ever compare to you, forever in my heart ♪
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become part of your journey ♪
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
MkvDrama.net